Mohammad H. Ghasemzadeh, PMP

http://www.mozadeh.com • 88 San Fernando St. Suite 1906, San Jose CA • hosein88@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Mohammad has built three products (two mobile apps and one web app) from scratch to over fifty thousand users and counting. Mohammad has also worked as an internal consultant for a Fortune-500 bank and as an external consultant for PWC Management Consulting, helping clients improve their operations, increase sales, satisfy regulatory requirements and cultivate innovation within their organization. Mohammad is a certified PMP and a Full-Stack Developer with expertise in the following programming languages: Android Java, JavaScript, CSS, Android XML, PHP and SQL.

EDUCATION

UC Berkeley (Berkeley, USA), Master of Information & Management Systems, 2014 - Present

- 1st place and audience award UC Berkeley Haas PLAY Hackathon (largest conference hosted by Haas)
- Graduate Student instructor for two courses: Principles of Business, Applied innovation at Haas School of Business

Sharif University of Technology (Tehran, Iran), B.Sc. Computer Engineering - Software, 2004 – 2008

EMPLOYMENT EXPERIENCE

CO-FOUNDER, SMARTIKY APPS SEP 2009 – PRESENT

- Built product roadmap, conducted numerous user interviews and worked on developing frontend and back-end of two mobile apps and one web app with an aggregate user-base of over 50,000 users
- Launched http://www.Cardstak.com, a platform that integrates LinkedIn and Eventbrite APIs and enables better networking. This platform has approx.10,000 users has been used for over 150 events and has generated over \$1000
- Launched Smart Mail (http://tinyurl.com/og6wmbr). This app allows users to delete content of sent email messages, notifies users when email message have been read and creates beautiful templates for messages. This app had up to 200 new (organic) downloads per day. This app is integrated with Gmail and Yahoo Mail
- Launched Smart Poll (http://tinyurl.com/pewkwmp), which was a social polling app and was featured on numerous blogs and app review websites. It is currently deactivated on Google Play. This app used Facebook APIs

PRICEWATERHOUSE COOPERS MANAGEMENT CONSULTING, TORONTO, CANADA SENIOR ASSOCIATE, MANAGEMENT CONSULTANT, DEC 2012 - MAR 2014

- Executed global market scan regarding best practices in mortgage lending and developed recommendations for improving sales and customer experience. Presented analysis to executives and received approval for implementation
- Analyzed survey responses from approximately two thousand executives and developed the Canadian Edition for PwC Global Innovation study with insights on executive plans, mindsets and investments in innovation
- Helped a Credit Union achieve efficiencies through developing a model for customer segmentation, building standardized practices for business centers and other tactical improvements
- Helped a leading financial institution to be compliant with FATCA (Foreign Account Tax Compliance Act) regulations by classifying their entities and developing a high level governance and controls model

BANK OF MONTREAL FINANCIAL GROUP, Toronto, Canada Consultant, Business Process Improvement, OCT 2011 – NOV 2012

- Delivered lean training and created parts of training material as part of Operations Management Program for managers and senior managers
- Developed a library of information on previous projects utilizing best practices, allowing consultants to leverage knowledge gained during previous projects for future projects
- Recommended and designed a training phase and selection process for new recruits within Product Operations resulting in 25% less error rates in commercial lending process

AFRANET (Leading Internet Service Provider in Iran), Tehran, Iran Project Manager, FEB 2008 - JUL 2009

- Developed an intranet system by analyzing the needs of different divisions and organizing the conversion of major organizational workflows to electronic based systems. This project resulted in 30% reduction in turnaround times
- Led a team of 6 people to redesign and implement the company's website. This project resulted in a 45% increase in length of time users spent on website and 25% increase in number of visitors

ACTIVITIES AND INTERESTS

- Excellent snowboarder and basketball player (won numerous inter-collegiate titles)
- Expert in creating designs with Adobe Photoshop over 9 years of experience